icsa lombar is now on our radar it was a
good quarter for the company Net premium
witnessed a Healthy Growth while
combined ratio has also improved we have
Mr gopal balandra CFO and cro at is
Lombard now joining us to take some
questions Mr baland good morning good to
have you with us here thanks very much
you know I have to begin by asking you
uh what the recent tragic floods that
happened in sikim uh and some of the
other sort of you know incidents which
have happened recently
what has been is have you been able to
put an estimate to your exposure uh to
these and uh would you like to share
that with us yeah so good morning
Prashant and good morning to all your
viewers uh so I think when you look at
it in the context of uh some of this
flood or cat events uh in the past as I
have mentioned even earlier we should
talk about maybe at best one or two cat
events in a year today possibly what we
are encountering is maybe one or two
quarters every uh one or two events
every quarter uh so thanks to maybe some
of the climate change related events uh
having said that I think in quarter one
we had the Cyclone Bor jooy which had a
significant impact uh on the net claims
for us we had an impact of almost about
35 crores in Quarter Two I think we had
seen a lot of events particularly let's
say some of the floods that happened in
the northern part of the country now
there again obviously we did get
impacted we had roughly close to about
800 claims getting intimated and in so
far as the net impact of those losses on
our pnl that number was roughly about 48
crores uh so every quarter I think we do
get to see some of these cat events play
out uh in so far as the way we manage
the overall exposure is we also put in
place uh adequate reinsurance support so
that uh in the event we find losses
exceeding a particular threshold they
are kind of reinsured and we get
recoveries from the uh reinsurance
Partners uh but on balance I think when
you look at it uh what we have also seen
consequent to some of these increased
catastrophic losses there have also been
an increase in reinsurance rates and
therefore to that extent logically this
should also translate into better
pricing in so far as the overall Market
is concerned so 35 CR net impact in q1
because of events 48 crores you said in
Q2 in Q3 what should that number
approximately be would it be in the same
range or would it be much higher very
difficult P I think we will obviously
have to wait for let's say these events
to play out I think we only expect that
uh the scale and the magnitude of these
events possibly kind of uh are limited
uh but uh we will have to wait and see
maybe we'll be able to give a better
guidance when we announce numbers in
Q3 uh sir I believe you had given a
guidance of High Teens growth for the
gross direct premium income um does that
stay for the full
year so Rema again when you look at it
you are absolutely right I think uh
let's look at it from let's say or half
year or let's say even on a quarter on
quarter basis uh on a half year basis
the industry grew at roughly about 15%
we grew at about 18% uh for Quarter Two
if you look at I think the industry grew
slightly lower at about 12 and half 13%
pH that I think we grew at about 17% um
now when you look at the longer term
growth trajectory for the GI sector for
the last 23 years the industry has grown
at about 15 16% uh so there is no reason
why this Market as I said even for the
half year has grown at almost about
similar numbers as 15% or thereabout so
even for a full year basis the
expectation is with uh activities
happening across lines of businesses
Market should continue to grow in high
teams and whenever the markets generally
have grown responsibly Isis Lombard has
generally delivered 100 to 200 basis
points growth over and above the market
growth rates so hence that's the kind of
trajectory that we would kind of largely
work with and see the development of the
market as
uh on an ongoing
business all right hi sir morning uh you
know could you give us a couple of
numbers so what is your combined ratio
likely to move to it's cooled off 120
basis points out where do you end this
year with and also your claim ratio that
as well has come off close to 200 basis
points yeah so Nigel again I think when
you look at it uh from what we spoke
even last time I think we have spoken to
the market towards bringing down our
combine which used to be in that range
of around 104% plus earlier
uh the objective is to kind of bring it
down to 102% by the end of fi25 and we
are pretty much on course to in that
direction to get our combined down to
those levels in terms of the split
between the loss ratios and the expense
ratios will be purely a function of uh
what kind of mix of businesses that we
write so very difficult to specifically
call out in terms of what exactly could
be the loss ratio and what could be the
expense ratios but broadly if you look
at it on from a loss ratio perspective
we have kind of stained in a range of
around between 70 to 75% in that kind of
range and when you look at the expense
of Management number let's say for this
half year we are operating at an expense
of management closer to about
26.9% uh so but well on course towards
the objective of combined going down to
102 by the end of next financial
year uh sir you operate across various
segments motor Health crop crop your
presence is you know quite uh you know
less uh but amongst all these segments
where is it that you are seeing maximum
growth where is it that competitive
intensity has picked up can you just
give us some industry trends that you've
observed over the last three months and
what can you guide for the second half
so it's a great question uh so look
at segments that you rightly mentioned
whether it's motor health or commercial
lines all of them are preferred segments
for us and directionally I think when we
look at the opportunity that each of
these segments presents in in the market
context is very very positive and within
that I lomard obviously as I said wants
to kind of Leverage on this incremental
growth potential if you look at each of
these segments so let's take Health as a
category for example uh for the half
historically also in general I think we
have been kind of growing quite well on
this segment uh but if you look at just
for the half year the industry grew at
roughly about 24 25% on the health as
overall category Isis Lombard grew at
almost close to about 31% now this
growth in health was aided by growth
both in retail Health as well as let's
say corporate or employe employee uh
segment so in that sense I think we have
been able to have an outperformance in
so far as the corporate Health segment
is concerned but on an increasing basis
we are also witnessing slightly elevated
levels of competition in this particular
segment and therefore we will see how
things play out for the rest of the year
in so far as the commercial lines is
concerned which is the typical product
offerings that you make to a corporate
whether it is with respect to fire
engineering Marine cargo liability etc
etc there again I think we have had an
industry beating number industry has
grown at a maybe a high single digit
number our growth has been upwards of 16
17% and this is something not just this
year consistently over the last several
years we have been able to have
outperformance on Commercial lines as a
category and we believe even the
trajectory going forward looks very very
promising given the scale of uh
infrastructure Investments and
activities that is happening on the
ground uh should kind of help us to
sustain similar level of uh
outperformance on the commercial lines
the third category on motor again if you
look at that's one segment we have been
bit guarded given the relative higher
higher competitive intensity that we
have seen in this segment operating
particularly over the last 18 to 24
months but off late I think we have seen
a bit of uh easing happening in the
market it Still Remains competitive and
hence we have been taking a guarded
stance but on a sequential basis when
you look at our growth trajectory again
it is looking very very promising for
example we grew in quarter one on motor
by roughly about 5 6% quarter 2 our
growth is about 11% and the gap between
us and and the industry growth rate has
significantly got narrowed and with now
let's say the changes in the expense of
management guideline playing out and
roughly 50% of the Market operating at a
threshold higher than the stipulated
levels uh if once that course corrects
we should also be able to get better
growth rates and towards the end of the
year we should see even growth in motor
for us in line with the industry numbers
for Isis Lombard the expense of
management has been well within the
threshold okay all right on that
optimistic note then we let you go at
that thanks so much sir for joining in
and giving us all those details and
wishing you all the best for the second
half of this
[Music]
fiscal